# ARTIOM DOLGHI

781-888-0458, dolghi.artiom@gmail.com LinkedIn, GitHub, YouTube

#### **SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with experience in a variety of programming languages and development/analysis tools

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Python, Java, C++, C, SQL, HTML, CSS, Lua

Tools/Software: Pandas, NumPy, Jenkins, AWS, Git, Bitbucket, Jira, Jupyter Notebooks, TIBCO Spotfire, PL/SQL,

Excel, WinSCP, Diango, Workload Scheduler (TWS), ServiceNow

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Wellington Management**

### **Software Engineer**

07/2022 - Present

- Develop tools and features for use within the business using Python and libraries like Pandas and NumPy, as well as many internal libraries, utilizing large amounts of data
- Enhance existing features by making code more efficient, clean, and adding new elements based on business requirements
- Engage in the full development process, including coding, debugging, testing, building, and deploying, going from the local development environment all the way to production
- Write documentation, keep it updated when modifications are made, and answer any related questions
- Create dynamic and static tables using Python and SQL to load data into databases
- Use a workload scheduler to create, modify, and delete jobs and schedules that point to code
- Set up development environments and tools on machines
- Contribute to and manage tools with regular release dates and deadlines
- Manage and assist in production releases
- Coordinate with other developers, as well as data analysts and members of various business teams

## **Lionbridge Technologies**

### **Content Analyst**

06/2019 - 07/2022

- Analyzed and provided feedback on text, web pages, images and other types of information for leading search engines using data sets and AI software
- Assessed content by quality, level of engagement, and user experience

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Suffolk University, Boston MA

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

09/2018 - 05/2022

# **INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS**

- Created a web application using Django (Python, HTML, CSS) that connected to a MySQL database and allowed users to enter SQL commands from a front-end interface to search and modify the database
- Built and maintained multiple virtual in-game servers in Lua using server hosting services and SFTP tools.
  This involved designing and coding a custom game environment with its own story and economy, moderating player activity and taking player feedback into account, as well as working with various frameworks and plugins to create a smooth and engaging experience
- Developed a custom addon in Lua from scratch within a game environment that functioned as a cooking oven where the player could pick recipes, provide ingredients, and receive a finished item on completion. This involved utilizing the base props from the game, coding the logic for client side, server side, and shared files, as well as creating a UI on the entity itself which allowed for player interaction

# **OTHER SKILLS**

Languages: English (Native, Fluent), Russian (Native, Fluent)